Email: jordan.figu@gmail.com Portfolio: https://adamofig.com

Tel: 5524250154



Cloud architect, full expertise of Google Cloud, web and mobile application development, Angular expertise, leadership, diligence and team player, diverse use of technology stacks as Java Spring, JS Node, Python Django, Docker and more, technical process implementation (data pipelines, continuous integration) data troubleshooting, analysis, visualize, data mining and machine learning models, fully committed for learning and sharing, my YouTube channel dataclouder has been recently launched.

Education

Computer Engineer Degree

Languages

- · Spanish (Native)
- ·English (B2 by Anglo)
- · Portuguese (Beginner)

Certificate

· May 2019 Google Professional Cloud Architect

Skills



Leadership



Cloud Solutions



Web Frontend Development



Mobile Hybrid Development



Backend Development



Data Mining

Technologies

- Angular
- · HTML
- · CSS
- TypeScript
 - JavaScript
- · SASS

- · Ionic
- · jQuery
- · RXIS

- · Java
- · Spring Boot · MySQL
- · C#
- · .Net Core
- · Sql Server

- Node
- Express
- BigQuery

- Python
- Django
- · Git

- · Data Studio · Pandas Azure

- · Colab Firebase
- · GCP

- · Unity
- · C
- DevOps · PHP
- · Google VR
- · Gnu/Linux
- Arduino · Unix
- · Visual Studio

- Jupiter

- · Batch/Shell · Google Maps

Job Experience

Capgemini Feb 2018 - Current Job (Angular, Spring Boot, Google Cloud, Python, ETL)

Consulter in GNP Insurance, is the largest insurer in Mexico

- · Architecting and resolve complex solutions on Google Cloud
- · Data mining and migrations
- · In project maintenance
- · Technical coacher for diverse technologies
- · Software development lead
- · Responsible for successful deployments

Opalo (Angular, Unity, Firebase, Aframe)

A company dedicated to developing immersive experiences using virtual and augmented reality technologies

- · Technology and system architect
- · Development of landing web page and service platform
- · Development of augmented reality application
- · Real-time database linking
- · Continuous research on 3D technologies

QueMesa Oct 2016 - Dec 2017 (Angular, Ionic, Azure, .Net)

A startup whose goal was to fill empty tables of restaurants using a mobile app for booking and get discounts.

- · Responsible for mobile application developing
- · Integration with backend and mapping data
- · Updates to database and backend code
- · Responsible for admin dashboard
- · Active cooperation in Quemesa projects

CGMA Ago. 2015 - Apr. 2016 (Jquery, Appcelerator, Codelgniter)

Government area responsible for modernizing management services for Mexico City

- · Analysis and user description from Mexico City Citizens
- · Development of "Taxi Seguro" Module for "Smart CDMX" APP (Real-time tracking and security app for taxi users)
- · Development of Backend for "Taxi Seguro"
- · Development of Real-Time Visualization trips Dashboard